has a lane 1510 touchdown
Chargers.
What's up, guys? Welcome into a brand
new episode of Chargers Weekly. We are
presented by Splatterero. Doing this
thing virtual before the combine next
week. Matt Muddy Smith joining me from
the East Coast, man. Little East Coast
swing a
>> little bit. Yeah. My uh youngest
daughter is a musician and uh she's got
a little East Coast tour with a band
called True Blood and it's been really
fun. Boston on Sunday, New York City on
uh Wednesday. Now we're in DC and we'll
be in Philly, you know, DC Philly for
the weekend. So, pretty fun stretch.
Incredible crowds. It's been uh really
fun. I'm just driving the van and, you
know, moving some gear around. That's
about the extent. Paying the bills.
That's uh
>> paying the bills, baby.
>> Yeah, that's my role in all this, Chris.
>> Oh, I love it, man. She's so talented.
It's uh it's cool to see all her success
and see you guys doing a tour, man. It's
pretty pretty awesome.
>> Yeah, it's been a lot of fun. A lot of
fun. Energy has been incredible. Saw a
lot of old friends from for people that
don't know. I used to be in the music
business. So, guys that I haven't seen
in 20 25 years, some of them. And just
like old friends, you know, you you
immediately make that connection again
and it feels like you saw them last
week. So, it's been been pretty special.
A lot of fun. But I'll be in the combine
on Monday just like you and know listen
to a bunch listen to DJ's uh conference
call on the way down here from New York
City.
>> Listen to it, too.
>> Yeah. So, we're we're ready to roll.
Still uh still deep into this thing.
>> Yeah. No question. Three podcasts next
week, guys. So, uh I feel like we just
did this uh a couple of weeks ago uh
last year in Indie. Joe Ortiz is going
to join us. Chad Alexander going to join
us. a ton of different analysts from
ESPN, Pro Football Focus, some of our
friends. So, really looking forward to
kind of diving into this draft and I
thought it would be appropriate, Marty,
to maybe answer some fan questions
before we get to the combine, kind of
set the table for free agency, maybe a a
combine and draft primer. And, uh, we
got a ton of questions. Uh, so let's
just get right to them. Uh, the first is
from Newemi. I think this kind of sets
the table. uh at life of MIM16. In order
to maximize the amount of available cap
space in free agency, when can fans
expect roster cuts to start being
announced or will it just be spread out
like in years past? So, it's a great
question and I think it's going to
obviously add cap space to whatever the
Chargers have now. I think they're
second in the NFL and cap space with
around 87 million. Um, and that could go
up. And money before you you get into
this I'll just listen if there's a
there's a few moves that could be made
to to save some money. If you release
Makai Beckton 9.7 million in cap savings
Boseman 5.8 million Dley 5 million uh
Bud Dupri 3.49 million. It's just the
way it's set up. If you gave uh Derwin
an extension that cap number which is
24.6 million this year that could
probably go down a little bit in 2026.
And there's some other things you can do
as well.
>> Yeah, I think you hit them all, Chris. I
think those are the obvious ones. Mai
Beckton being the biggest number,
Bradley Boseman being the second biggest
number. And I think when you talk about
those two players, um, sort of either
there in the case of Beckton, lack of a
availability last year, just way too
many injuries, and it's been that way
throughout the course of his career. Um,
and then with with Bradley Boseman, even
though the availability was there, I
think the ability was lacking a little
bit. just the fit, right, for scheme and
and what Mike McDaniel likes to do, what
his offensive lines look like, you know,
just sort of that more athletic
offensive line. Really want guys that
can move around, especially at the
pivot, which we know Bradley a little
bit more of that strong sort of anchor
gap scheme kind of guy. And with just
sort of the way the pass pro went last
year, I think you're probably looking at
close to 15 million bucks right there.
In the case of Bud, to me, it's it's
probably a result of what they want to
do moving forward, and that is likely
get Tuli and Ooway and hopefully Khalil
and all three of them locked up on new
deals, and that means every cent's going
to going to count for that particular
room. Um, I think it's way different
than year one with with with Coach
Harbaugh and Joe Ortiz, right? When they
had to figure out what to do with
Khalil, what to do with Joey, what to do
with Keenan, what to do with Mike
Williams because they needed money. You
know, right now they're sitting on 80
million bucks and it's just a matter of,
hey, what happens? You know, if it's
this big for people that are watching
and all of a sudden if it becomes this
big with the OA, Tart, Derwin,
restructure, two lee ext, you know, can
we get it back out to here for outside
free agents at the center position, at
the guard position? What do you do with
Zion? You know, are there is there a
fullback out there that you need a
couple million bucks for? Like that sort
of stuff. That's when you pull those
levers. But I I think the ones you
mentioned um just probably make a little
bit too much sense. Like I always hate,
you know, because essentially you're
firing someone. I don't like doing that.
But I think you just you look at it and
it's just kind of staring at you right
there in the face. But you know, the the
legal tampering period, I don't think
they call it that anymore. I you know,
because it was such a crazy name. I
think they call it the negotiating
period is about week and a half, two
weeks away. So they've got time to to
figure that out. And I think I always
feel like this organization I think it's
top down that that you know John Spanos
and his you know and Dean and and who
whomever's been that front office you
know whether it was Tom or now Joe I
think they've always been good with the
players like hey let's if we know we're
going to move on let's get you out there
so you can kind of hit that first wave
and and maybe you know recoup that money
and get yourself back into this. Yeah, I
I hate talking about other people's
money, but these guys know when they
sign the contracts that it's a very high
probability that it's not guaranteed
that following year. And just it's just
the name of the game. It's what the cap
uh the cap is in the NFL. And you know,
buddy, there's a couple other uh levers
they could pull. You know, Justin
Herbert and Rashawn since they both both
have guaranteed salaries. Spo says that
you can you can convert uh both of them
add that void year and get 18.2 2
million in cap space with Justin and
13.4 with Slater. I know they've done
that in the past with certain players to
kind of convert uh money into bonus
money. Uh so if that's something that
they need to do, if they if they want to
be a little bit more aggressive and
bring in free agents or maybe resigning
some of their own guys, I think you
could kind of push a couple of those
buttons as well.
>> Yeah, look, I we I brought it up last
week because I'm still taking incoming
for it and I think people just that the
the quarterback is the bank. We just saw
it in Kansas City with with Patrick,
right? And that obviously was a
different situation because of how much
he was on the hook for. You knew that
this year was going to be that
restructure year, but for for Justin,
look, the Caleb Williams extension, the
Drake May extension, these things are
going to be coming and those guys are
going to get more than Dak Prescott. I
guarantee it that that number is one at
least one of those two. I mean, Drake
May second in MVP voting. I can promise
you that that number is going to be at
least 62.5 million bucks. So if you just
want to get ahead of it and you can
convert it and you can give yourself
more money while getting ahead of that
number. So the next time you know when
you have to do it anyway in two years
instead of it being 67 and a half
million bucks, you're at 60 and a half
million bucks and feel pretty good about
you doing right by your guy. Another
great point, you know, by you. If you
need to free up some more money, you
know, that's there. But I think the
thing, one thing that they do have right
now, Chris, is, you know, they've got
the cap space. So, I think,
>> yeah,
>> if if if their big ticket item this off
season outside of the the team is that
center, if they want to get into that
Tyler Linderbomb sweep stakes, I can
tell you right now, it's going to be a
sweep stakes. He's going to be the
highest paid center in the league.
that's what you want to get into and
you've got to worry about Derwent Tulie,
Khalil Ooway, then that may be something
that they look at.
>> And what a segue. We we probably got
five or six questions about the center.
Uh I I'll read off a couple because I
think we can kind of loop some of these
all together. Uh uh Grester, my buddy
from CBSLA, who's a huge Charger fan.
What are we going to do at center? Uh
let's see. We got uh Boltz 10213. Would
you rather address guard or center in
free agency if you can only do one? And
then there's another one. Would you
rather have the Chargers go after Linder
Bomb and draft a guard or sign a player
like Conor McGovern that can play center
and guard for less and then draft best
player available? So really a lot of
Linder Balm Conor McGovern talk. I feel
like Linder Bomb, we talked about it
last week. He's the prize. He's the bell
of the ball and you're gonna have to pay
a heavy price to get him.
>> Yeah. And you know, he's going to have
his choice. That's that's ultimately
what it comes down to. No matter what
the Chargers do, how much they want,
they know it's going to cost him. If
that's the guy they want, they they're
well aware they're going to have to pay
him. And it's going to be a big number.
And I think it'll just come down to does
he want to stay in Baltimore? Does he
want to follow John Harbaugh to New
York? Does he want to sign with the
Chargers? Does he want to go play for
Dan Campbell in in Detroit? I mean,
there are going to be no less than five
teams, I think, minimum, that are going
to be in the the linder bomb sweep
state. So, you know what that's going to
look like. Um, you're going to write a
big check. And I think, you know, the
name that they mention in there, Conor
McGovern, seems to be the second player
on that list. And so, I think the
question sort of becomes is okay, what's
the money and what's the drop off? You
know, how how much better is Tyler
Linderbomb than if you think it's
McGovern is the second guy on that list?
I know it's it's not like last year
where you had Grace Ael who was center
guard versatile and you knew was going
to go in the first round probably the
top 25 picks. He ends up going to the
top 20 picks. I don't get the sense, and
this is based on kind of what DJ, I know
he was asked about center on his call,
um, that he just did, the media call
that he just did, um, and just kind of
asking around, it doesn't look like
there's a first round center here. It
doesn't look like there's a real high
second round center in this draft. So, I
think if you want to have some stability
at that position, you're either going to
try to win that sweep stakes and
understand whoever doesn't win
litterbomb is going to be willing to pay
for McGovern. like that's that's the
reality of it. You know, they're they're
going to write that check for McGovern
as well. So, you're going to pay a
premium there. I do think there's I do
think there's varying options at guard,
right? I think you'll have the the upper
tier, which I think Zion is going to be
in that upper tier of guard. And then
you're going to have a number of
options. Does is Kevin Zeitler finally
going to come around to playing on the
West Coast? You know, can you get a
one-year fix there? Is it Camalo? Is it
Wyatt Teller? Is it Baton? some of these
older players that you feel I mean we've
talked about it so much right Chris you
don't need elite elite especially
because you've got Joe Walt and Rashan
Slater right next to him so if you can
find league average man you want to talk
about building a great line you just
can't have a weak spot u and I think
there's plenty of opportunities where
whether it's Edwards at the higher end
or Zion at the higher end or you know in
that middle tier
of, you know, Camalo and and Teller and
that sort of level. Um, I I do think
there are plenty of options there. And
it does look like guard is in a much
better place in the draft than center.
And so, you're going to be able to find
some some pretty good guards. It feels
like, you know, in that if you want to
go high second, even first um with the
Penn State guard that everyone seems to
be high, but he looks a little bit more
like that Mer gap scheme type. I don't
know. I have not dug into it yet. That's
what the combine's for. When I have a
chance to talk to all the guys uh that I
used to be around and just kind of get
pick their brains and find out who they
like and what they like so I can kind of
get all that collected for the people
that that want to know. It's me just
sharing information that I've got from
them. So that's all going to happen when
I get down to Indie.
>> Yeah, no question. You know, with
center, it just makes me feel like
Hortiz and uh Coach Harbaugh, they're
going to zone in and and home in on
center at free agency because you have
you have to get an upgrade there. And
it's really coming down to Linderbomb,
McGovern, and I guess Cade Mazize from
Carolina would be like your third center
in free agency. It's it's not a a robust
center market in free agency either in
addition to just being able to I think
DJ said maybe in the third round you
could attack the center position.
There's a couple of guys that you could
plug and play uh and they could be
starters in 2026. But you just look at
Linderbomb. Uh I I kind of did a side by
side between him McGovern and Cade
Mazize. Uh Linderbomb's pass block grade
was 22 out of 40 63.4 before, but his
his run block rate 83.7 80.3 overall.
Conor McGovern uh better much better
pass blocking grade 73.4 65.2 run
blocking grade 69.1 and then you have
Maize who's just a tier behind those
guys at 69.4 passing block uh 58.4 and
62.4 overall. But all three would be
pretty significant upgrades from the
production that they got last year at
the position. So, you know, if I'm if
I'm Joe Joe Ortiz, it seems like they're
going to be in the mix for litter bomb
uh and or McGovern and just see if one
of those guys will end up wearing a a
lightning bolt on their helmet.
>> Look, I I think they know that it's not
just, you know, to me like that position
is so important just for the mental
health of the team. you know, it's it's
been it's been at a level the last two
years that has led to their quarterback
taking way too many hits and getting
injured, you know, getting nicked up and
for that matter, yeah, injured way too
much. Um, and so to me, that's that's
why we talk about perhaps one of the the
least flashy positions that we could
possibly talk about, right, is center.
But I always point to look at what
Justin Herbert and Corey Linsley did
together, how special that connection
was, you know, and and and what that
meant. And so for me, that's why I do
think, you know, Tart is now done. I
think Oay is priority one. I think that
thing do not let him get to the market.
Figure out what that number is with his
people and him and let's not let him let
do not get in a bidding war there. And
then as soon as that's done, bang, get
to get to center. To me, that's that
they already got one of the three
priorities out of the way with Tart,
making sure they didn't lose another guy
like they did Puna. Let's get that
squared away. Now, let's keep our young,
incredibly bright future pass rusher at
a premium position locked up. And then
let's go get a center and figure out how
we drop those two guards in. If it's
Zion, if it's taking a step back because
you overspent on center from Zion or,
you know, figuring that whole thing out.
Yeah, you know, Mike McDaniel's no doubt
going to give his input, he and Butch
Barry, about the the type of guards and
offensive linemen that they think are
best suited for this system. And that's
the one position, group money, that it
just feels like it's not a blowup
situation because Alton Slater are
coming back, but it seems like that
needs to be a complete reset across the
line. Um, you mentioned Oay. Uh, a lot
of questions about Mack and Oay. Uh, our
guy Ed Labar, uh, what are the chances
they can keep both Mack and OA and get a
center and guard in free agency? Uh,
Kurt Macintosh, is it more important
that the team addresses the O line in
the offseason or resign extend defensive
players like Mack and Oay and obviously
extend DJ. Uh, and then will we get one
more year from Khil Mack? That's Tom
Little. Uh, so there's there's no
question that Oay and Mack on the minds
of a lot of Chargers fans. Uh that's a
guy who, you know, ironically I I would
I would think maybe Baltimore's in the
mix for his services as well as a few
other teams. But uh what Adaf did last
year to have no sacks in Baltimore, come
to Los Angeles and put on a a pretty
good performance, he's going to make a
lot of money somewhere.
>> Look, I think for for OA, you know that
Jesse Mer is going to try to get him
back. uh he needs edge rushers. And
Chris Olirri basically told us I'm I'm a
pupil of Jesse Miner. So that's that's
what I am. That's the defense I'm
running. That's the guy that I lean on.
So you know how important getting home
with four is. And they do not have pass
rush in Baltimore on those edges. They
traded a way away. So I don't know if he
takes that as a slight. You know, uh the
cost is still there. He's the guy that
got rid of him. And you know, didn't
want to pick up the fifth option. didn't
thought he was, you know, worth trading
for a safety, you know, a nonpremium
position versus a super premium position
and a and and a fifth round pick. So
maybe there's some resentment there on
that front. Um, and maybe he likes LA,
maybe he likes playing with Tulie. We we
know the hockey assist sacks that that
Tuli's able to afford you when he's
playing in that NASCAR package inside of
of O0 or Khalil. So I hope that's the
case. I think it'll be a serious
priority. The one thing I would caution
is, you know, edge rushers, wide
receivers, offensive line, these numbers
can get crazy. They can get crazy in a
hurry. And that's why I think they just
probably paid if if you're really kind
of talking about the open market. They
maybe they paid a million dollar per
year premium on Tart just to make sure
he didn't get to the market. You know, I
think if you're willing to do that and
instead of handing him 18 million bucks
a year, maybe you're just going to hand
him 20 per just to keep away, you know,
from taking those meetings and and
locking him up. And I think Khalil, I've
got to believe just the way that coach
Harbaugh talks about him and and Joe
Ortiz talks about him, it's going to be
up to him. You know, you want to come
back, we want you. We'll pay you a fair
wage. Um, and if you want it, we want
it. Let's make it happen. you know, and
and I I'd be very surprised if he went
anywhere else. Uh it just feels like
this is, you know, unless it was
Baltimore, unless it there was a Jesse
thing there with him as well.
>> And I don't know about, you know,
Chicago, a place where he played for
four years, who's actually on the up and
up. It's is that is that a potential
destination? I I think he's I think he's
so important to to 2026. We obviously
know that that may be his last year. Uh,
but just what what he means that kind of
the DNA of the defense just to have that
presence in the room, you know, and we
can get into the draft. I think that
edge is a is a position in the draft
that the Chargers absolutely have to
look at just for the future. Uh, but but
to get Khalil back at a at a reasonable
price that that's fair to him, but also
maybe allows a little bit more
flexibility to get Tuli paid and and
Adaf as well. um if if they can kind of
compromise on that, having all three of
those guys together in 2026, I think
will be big.
>> Yeah. Look, I think for the the way you
you know, you work it is is you want the
the draft and you want free agency to
work in concert, right? And so you have
an opportunity to lock up two very young
edge rushers. You don't want to lose and
you don't want to lose Tuli. They're
young. Like, so you're good. I know it's
a deep-edged class and I think okay if
you do lose them then you can dip back
in but but why use that valuable asset
on something that you already have and
it's not like oh let's just let's put a
band-aid on it for one more year and
just get Khalil back for one more year.
Well yeah Khalil is you know the the
meat of your edge room is is Tuli and
and Ooway. I know it sounds crazy to
talk about a likely first ballot hall of
famer and Khalil Mack being the gravy,
but that's kind of what he is, right?
It's like you recognize, okay, this is
this is probably a one it's a
year-by-year thing. You have no idea
what the what the extended future is
going to hold, but to me, the fact that
you have these two, you know, Tuli's
still I mean, I don't mean it literally,
but man, he's a kid. He's 25. like you
know this dude is like that's
>> so to me that's where
>> I think even though it's deep I think
it's more like interior defense would
make sense of 22 you know grabbing that
guard 22 getting a getting a premier
number one corner like even though it's
a deep edge draft like that to me is a
little bit more of a draft me draft me
draft me you've got these guys just give
them their money and let's use the draft
assets on something
It's so funny you say that he's 25. It
just it's a it almost blows your mind
because this kid is it Aake Messador
from Miami. He's going to be a 25 year
old rookie, right?
>> And the fact that the fact that Tulie's
put in all this work in the NFL already
and you know made his first Pro Bowl,
it's pretty incredible. Uh this uh this
next question is from Dom on IG. What do
you all think of Daniel Jeremiah mocking
Kenyan Sadiq, the tight end to the
Chargers? I just heard DJ talking about
him and he said that he's he's kind of a
notch below the guys that were drafted
high last year in in Warren and Lovelin,
but he did make a compelling case just
to give Mike McDaniel an extra piece in
uh in the passing game. And obviously
Sadique can block as well, but just a
it'd be a fun piece, but I know DJ's got
to do a million of these block drafts.
>> Yeah, he does. And and you don't want
them to be the same. Um, but I look I
think I think it was uh our friend
Steven from Guiltiest Charge that posted
it. It was pretty funny. He said uh I
saw the tweet. It said something like
for whatever reason the last few years
DJ's 2.0 has been spot-on for the
Chargers. Those are you know Amarian
Hampton last year was his 2.0 pick and
and for whatever reason that's the way
it's it's worked out uh year after year
with with the way he does his mock. So,
you know, this is 2.0 know and it's
Sadiq and two I think it was Lee Hunter
in 10 the DTackle but um how would I
feel about that? Yeah, I mean look
you've seen what what Kyle Shanahan has
done with with George KD. You've seen
what Mike McDaniel did with Darren
Waller last year, you know, and and so
to me I I think they probably you know
you mentioned Will Dley. It's a $5
million number. I was very surprised
with the way they or the way they didn't
use him last year. I always felt like
Will's a really good blocker. You know,
you don't want him to have 80 targets,
that's for sure. But he's pretty darn
good on those little wide receiver
screens and as your you know, if you
don't want to use a sixth offensive
lineman to use to use Will. So, um I
think Arande made some made some gains
in that in that category, but um you
know, the one issue with Sadikas drops.
He he's got a a I would euphemize it by
saying an unhealthy number of drops that
that is a little concerning. The
athleticism is incredible. Um he's not
he's not 66 250. He's not that tight
end. You know, he's
>> he's 6'3, you know, 240. That's the
tight end he is. So, I think it's, you
know, that's but but again, I think what
DJ's saying makes perfect sense, which
is some Mike McDaniel special, like,
"Hey, man, what do you want?" And it
seems like if you can get the other
stuff squared away in uh in free agency
that he'd be like, "I want that. Let me
let me let me get my hands on that and
let me think about both him and out
there at the same time, you know?" But
to me ultimately I just I feel like but
I say this every year and you know what
you might have a a question so I don't
mean to steal somebody's question with
my Ian Mai beanie on paying homage to
one of the all-time great musicians from
the Washington DC area. Um
>> there we go. I I think um I just it
makes so much sense to trade back with
just five picks. If one of those edge
rushers slides, if someone's got a fancy
for Sadique and they want to grab them,
um and you can just pick up their second
and a third and now you got two twos and
a three, like based on what they're
looking for, I think some depth in that
linebacker room, interior defensive
line, interior offensive line. to me,
bing, bang, boom, you can fill three
spots, you know, a two for one sort of
deal right there. Um, so I guess that's
kind of where to me Sadiq feels a little
bit more like a luxury like little
here's a little cherry we're dropping on
top, man.
>> You know, where I still feel like
>> I agree with that,
>> but money I I feel like we saw enough
from Aronda that I think he could take
another step with Mike McDaniel. And I I
also think that there's some some guys
in free agency. We'll get to that. I
think this part of the next question. Uh
but I I don't know if if Sadi is is the
absolute slam dunk guy that you need in
2026. I know that and DJ said this too,
Joe takes the best player available. You
know, if it's if he's the best player
available, it's a pretty good chance
that they're going to take him. Um but
it kind of dubtales into this next
question from Chargers District on IG.
Uh buddy, let's name the top three most
needed positions uh in the draft for the
Chargers. I I said O line, edge, and
corner. I'm curious what what you what
you think.
>> Yeah, I think O line interior obviously
interior line. I don't need to say that.
Um, you know, first round picks are
weird because they can say they're going
to draft best player available, but
there is that premium position, you
know, and I can remember having the
conversation about Q versus Dalton
Concincaid, and it was just like, dude,
your your your number one tight end is
going to make 12 million bucks. you
know, you're talking about a wide
receiver that's going to be, if they're
what you think they're going to be, it's
$25 million, you know, that you're that
you're trying to to save. I can save $15
million bucks with this pick. And that's
where Edge, I think with the Aaron Bakes
contract last year, now Oline, both
interior and edge and and tackle come
into play. Corner is you Sarder. Look at
the hall that they got for sauce
gardener, you know, when you can find
that number one elite corner. So, yeah,
I think I can say like, yeah, you know,
you've got Arande who is I think still a
developing player and it looks like he's
probably going to be the only guy in
that room based on how they didn't use
Will Dizzley last year. So you can make
the case, you know, from what DJ's doing
there that tight end is a need and tight
end's a very important position, you
know, in, you know, you think about what
Higgby has meant to the to the Rams,
what KD has meant to the 49ers, what
Waller meant to the to the Dolphins,
like it is a very important position in
this offense. So I I can understand, you
know, where that comes from. If you're
just asking me like what what do I see?
I see one and one a interior defensive
lineman and interior offensive lineman.
Those are the top two that that I see.
And if it's Banks or if it's Woods or if
it's Ione, you know, whoever that might
be at that spot, like to me, if you're
going to use that pick, I think those
are premium positions that that can pay
off at that at that selection spot.
Chargers Weekly is presented by
Splatterero, helping homeowners access
their home equity with no monthly
payments. Split offers home equity
investments. A better way to access the
cash you need from your home without
getting to go through a bank. Get a lump
sum of cash in exchange for a share of
your home's future value. Pay off debt,
renovate your home, and better your
life. Get your free cash estimate at
splitero.com/chargers.
Our next question from doublem uh 672.
uh one that requires a little homework.
Three free agents that you would like to
sign at interior offensive line, tight
end, and running back. And then we'll
get to the second part of his question.
So, I said this to you ahead of time,
buddy. Just three guys that I mean,
listen, we talked about Linderbomb
already. I think that's probably top of
the list for everybody, but interior
offensive line, tight end, and running
back in free agency.
>> Yeah. So, I'll start with tight end. And
I'm just thinking like in terms of cuts,
cut candidates. Um I think you you know
or or potential
trade sort of like I don't and again
there's new people there so I don't know
what Clint Kubak's going to do with
Michael Mayer like to me that's a
potential. Cole KT in Chicago is is got
some potential there. Um interior
offensive line I I think we already went
through them right whether it's
Linderbal or McGovern. Uh, Sioalo from
Pittsburgh, the guard. Edwards, the
guard. Edwards.
>> Um, I'm I'm fine with Wyatt Teller. Um,
Kevin Zitler if he's willing to to move
past the Mississippi and come to the
West, I'm fine with that as a one-year
fix. Um, look, I'm good bringing Zion
back, man. I think if you bring Zion
back and you drop a center, a solid
center next to him between Slater and
that center with his athleticism with
Mike McDaniel, I think he could be very
special. So, I'm good there. And then
what was the other one? Uh, tight end,
interior line,
>> running back.
>> I mean, I'm good. I'm good, man. I got
exclusive right free agents on Jared
Patterson and and Kimani Belle. I'm
good. I'm I'm I'm I'm looking at I'm
looking at Amaran as fluke. I think
those injuries were fluke injuries. You
know, the Washington game, he's got a
body that flies right into his freaking
ankle. Like, it's just It's not soft
tissue. It's like, oh, this guy was down
with a hammy three different times. It
wasn't that at all. Like to me, he is a
bellcow. He is a Bejon. He is a Seaquan.
He is Omar Young. You know, it ends with
N. So, it's got to be good. Um, so I I
think he's he's going to be a workhorse.
And like that's why I was kind of
disappointed in the in the uh New
England game. I was like, can we not can
we not get Jared Patterson to the edges
in this thing, man? Dude's got a hammer
like flashes, dude.
>> Right.
>> That Tennessee that tennis that
Tennessee game uh he had some some big
runs in that game. We saw some of it in
week 18. I I agree with you. I think
that they are good in that room. If if I
were to name a couple of guys,
>> I I think if you look at the history and
it's it kind of goes
>> in what you were saying with Amarian.
Amarian had a clean bill of health
throughout college.
>> Dashi Harris had a clean bill of health
his entire career. He popped his
Achilles. We know that is not a great
injury for a running back, but we saw JK
Dobbins come back from it and looked
pretty good and made some money and got
to Denver.
>> I think it it wouldn't hurt to give Naji
a shot at a very low cost. Uh somebody
that that Jim Harbaugh actually wanted
from the beginning. And if he if he
comes back in October, you know, he he
hurt himself in week three, which is end
of September. So you're already five,
six months into this thing. So, I think
that's a guy another another candidate
unrestricted free agent, Kenneth
Gainwell from Pittsburgh. I think there
was only four or five running backs in
the league this year that had more
receiving yards. So, I just look at a
guy that maybe is a little versatile out
of the back field to kind of spell
Amarian and and you have Kamani there as
well. So, that that's one name I I
thought of. Darren Waller is another guy
just a flyer that knows Mike McDaniel
and when he was playing he had success.
He's going to be 34 I think when when
training camp starts. But another
veteran in the room that I I feel like
vibed with Mike McDaniel and uh knows
that system. And then we we talked about
all these offensive linemen. You know
Edwards played for the Rams. He was on
that Super Bowl team. So familiar with
Los Angeles. Maybe you give him back to
the West Coast. But uh I like that
question. And then the second part of
it, money, your top three draft
prospects that you currently like for
this team. And this is probably better
suited to answer after the combine. And
we we do our factf finding mission, but
uh three guys that maybe at first glance
you would feel good at number 22.
Yeah, I think again my opinions on that
sort of stuff is typically a uh it's a
conglomerate of all the people that
study this stuff all year long and just
talking exactly
>> to them. But I mentioned, you know, I
mentioned two I think the two defensive
tackles, you know, Banks and Woods kind
of jump out um right away uh to me. I,
you know, like I said, I think interior
offensive line, you're probably better
off trading back. Um,
that kind of that that to me seems about
right. I don't think I don't think
there's a guard that you'd want to take
in that first round. I'm just going
through positions um as opposed to
players right now
>> in my brain.
>> Vega Vega Vega is the only one that
looks to be he may not even be
attainable for the Chargers. looks like
he may go in the top 15, top 20, but
that's the one guard. And you know, this
is why it's it's these are the guys I
want to learn more about next week. Like
h how how would he fit in a Mike
McDaniel system?
>> Um the uh the edge from Auburn who's 21
years old. We know Joe went to Auburn.
Kendrick Faulk, you know, is that a guy
that you can draft and even if you bring
Khalil and Adaf back, you know, it's a
player that maybe in year two takes that
leap. It seems to be a guy I think Mel
Kyper said he looks the part, right? But
the production was a little bit uneven.
Um the the guy Akeem Meador, 25year-old
uh edge from Miami, an older guy, and
then a couple of a couple of DBs um that
I saw play this year. uh uh Brandon Cece
from uh from South Carolina and then and
Colton Hood from Tennessee, the the
second uh defensive back uh from the
Volunteers that that'll likely go in the
first round. Just a couple of corners.
Uh Avon Terrell, uh AJ Terrell's brother
from Clemson is another corner that I
think DJ said would play in the nickel,
but can also play in the outside. So,
just those are the guys I think in the
range that I just want to learn more
about and see if they're a fit for what
Mike McDaniel and or Chris Ori want to
do.
>> Yeah. And I think the other thing not to
not to sleep on are the safeties. Uh,
and I was chatting with DJ about this
last week. Um, just kind of
>> he Toledo guy. He loves that Toledo guy.
>> Yes. McNeel Warren is the Toledo guy and
uh the Oregon kid Tiennaman is the other
one that's gonna just knock your socks
off. Um I is kind of what um I'm sort of
hearing. Again, that's just stuff me
dealing with DJ and talking to him a
little bit about that. But so like I
bring those guys up because you're like
well you got you know you've got Elijah,
you've got Derwin. is like think about
their versatility and think about what
Jesse Men are what what did he always
say he's like I don't care if it's a
corner if it's a slot corner if it's a
safety you know coach clink is still
there and it's what he always said just
want the best five guys who are the best
five guys and let's put the best five
guys and when you talk about those
particular guys uh you mentioned the one
out of Toledo Emanuel McNeel Warren as
I'm looking at it now yeah it's those
two it's McNeel Warren and I think it's
deniman is how you say hit something.
But that's now that I look at their
names, um, that's who DJ was talking
about that these are Derwin James types,
right? And if you want to put one there
and the other one can play up high or
the other one, hey, push this guy out to
the outside as as an outside corner and
you're playing the slot. And now you
don't know where it's coming from. You
you cannot figure out how this thing is
going to work. So yeah, I think those
those all work. Um, I'm just kind of
looking to see if there's anybody else
that that jumps out at me as
>> I I actually I I love that because you
know DJ kind of laid it out that you
know the the is it Nick Emman Worry from
Seattle. Yeah. Everybody's trying to get
their hands on a on a on a Derwin James
or a Kyle Hamilton. What if you had two
Derwin James though? What if you had
another guy who could do
>> some of the things that Derwin could do
and put him in the secondary? It's kind
of a fascinating look at maybe what the
secondary could look like. Yeah, I think
I know there's some people are kind of
down on Woods. I think I don't want to
you know what I don't want to kind of
tag. I feel like Jordan maybe it was
Jordan that was kind of talking about
being down a little bit on him, but man,
dude, you watch some of that stuff and
and that is an explosive dude. Um, and I
think he's going to be sitting there
when they pick Lee Hunter's another one
that I think is going to be a riser. And
you're talking about a guy who's 330 as
I'm going through this now. Um, and just
kind of trying to reignite my my brain
on um on who a couple of these. Yeah,
ABNE I think is going to be a riser, the
corner out of ASU and talking to some
people about him. I think those I I
think you've got um Ponds is another
guy, not a firstrounder, but I'm just
thinking of some of those slot corners
that can have some versatility to him.
Just really smart players. Um it's kind
of what I'm I'm getting at. So yeah, I
think there's Look, there's going to be
a good player. There's going to be a
good player at at 22. The one difference
this year is you may only have one
quarterback go ahead of him. So, you're
not going to get that quarterback. Yeah.
You know, kind of there's no quarterback
run this year.
>> Exactly.
>> Maybe Tai Simpson, but that may be the
only second maybe the second quarterback
taken in the first round. That may be a
would be a wrap. Uh original Shamaya
Mills music. Uh thoughts on drafting the
Penn State guard. We just talked about
that. Learn more about that guy next
week. I'm I'm uh interested to to
>> Yeah, I need to talk to Lance. I'm gonna
>> I'm gonna rap with Lance. Um but I in
just kind of chatting with them already
a little bit said that, you know, Mer,
big dude, still definitely athletic
enough to move around in what Mike
McDaniel wants to do. And as they merge
these two systems, you know, but that he
would have been like just a perfect fit
for what Greg Roman wants to do and
power and gap and that sort of scheme.
And you know that that's probably what
and and look, I think if you're drafting
a guard in the first round, you better
be darn sure that they are a special
special player like Grace Ael who was so
athletic and explosive when he went
through this whole process and you're
like, man, this guy is strong as an ox
and he's moving like that and he's got
center guard flexibility. Like that's
sort of what we're talking about. And
look, that's what Zion was when he came
out. Now remember, this was a dude that
is as strong as a bull, is incredibly
smart, incredibly athletic, and that's
the kind of guy that you take in the
first round. And that's why Zion went in
the first round, you know, and that's
why Green went before him because that's
just kind of how those guys profiled.
But I think that's one of those where
you got to be 100% certain that that's
what that person is because it's not
because you can find, you know, think
about Zack Frasier in the second round,
you know, for for Pittsburgh and what he
is now.
>> Yeah. So, it's kind of like you can find
those players
there as opposed to having to maybe
reach a little bit for a need.
>> Super Bowl 61 is coming to Los Angeles
and available now. You can secure
priority access to the best seat
locations and fan experiences through
Onloation, the official hospitality
provider of the NFL and proud partner of
the Los Angeles Chargers. By placing a
deposit, you'll be first in line for
official packages that include verified
Super Bowl tickets and premium instadium
parties featuring unrivaled
entertainment and hospitality. Select
packages even include the opportunity to
celebrate on the field postgame. For
more information, visit
onloationexp.com/support
or call 800591-9198.
All right. Uh, Tino. Tino from the
queue. Do you think the Chargers are
planning to use free agency primarily to
patch needs so they can draft purely the
best player available at 22? Or will
they have specific draft targets they're
counting on to fill starting roles? I
always feel like that's a that's a
question that has two answers, right?
yet you're you are always looking for
the best player available, but you're
also looking at a best player who can
help your team, especially if you're if
if it's a first round guy. You want that
person to help you right away. So, the
for free agency, yes, you supplement
your roster with it. Uh, I I think Joe
is as DJ illustrated in his call, he
just has a track record of taking the
best player available, but he also said
that people stack the board with needs
and then the best player available is
there.
>> Just so happens to be a need.
>> Exactly.
>> I go back to I go back to what Tom told
us and I believe it to be true for most
draft rooms and that is, you know,
you're drafting someone for four years,
not for 2026. So, there is so much value
in that first round pick monetarily that
you're getting someone that you think is
not just a starter, but you expect them
to be an elite level starter at their
position if you draft them in the first
round. And so,
>> y
>> the the worst thing you could possibly
do is say, "Oh, we got to plug this hole
this year." And then you're not picking
up the fifthear option on that player.
And so to me, that's like that's where
like the Amari and Hampton thing comes
in, right? Is running back a premium
position because of what they get paid?
No. But it's like this guy can be a
potential offensive player of the year
in the next four years if we if we give
him what we think we can and he has the
right things around him. That's how good
the talent is. So, let's just take them
and get this thing locked up for five
years here and and go on a run, you
know, as opposed to do we reach for a
guard? Do we reach for a corner? Just
take the best player. This guy's a top
15 talent. He's slid to us because he's
a running back and let's seize upon. And
I think if you ever had any question
about Ortiz, you know, doing the best
player available, it's clear in his
first two drafts, Joe Alt at five and
Amaron Hampton at 22 where they were
like, "Yeah, this is the guy. This is
the best player on our board. I know you
want the flashy Malik Neighbors, but
we've got Joe Alt graded higher, and
we're going to take him." Uh, same thing
with Amaran was was graded so much
higher than anybody else that was left.
There was one I think they said it was
the last first round grade they had left
on their board and there he was sitting
at 22.
>> And just think about how snake bitten
they were that to have both those guys
not participate in the playoff game. You
know with with Hampton playing one snap
just imagine how different that game
could have been. Jason Sprinkle senior
the probability that the defense takes a
step back is pretty high with coach Mter
gone. How important is the defense
during the draft? Is it focused on
offensive lineup grades or will there be
an early focus uh on fixing any
defensive concerns during the draft or
free agents? So, I think that there's
this degree of thinking that since
Jesse's gone, maybe it's not going to be
a top five unit and that that remains to
be seen. I think it's it's fair to, you
know, when you when you have a guy like
that leave your building, obviously
there's going to be a transition period.
Uh we we also believe that the offense
will take a a step up with Mike
McDaniel. So uh how do you answer that
question in terms of defense and you
know a lot of the same coaches are there
uh a lot of the same players are there.
It's just a matter of maybe using some
of this cap space to to bring in some
more impact players.
I think if you're just like to me if
you're just bringing everyone back um
like I think about what they what Dante
Jackson looked like last year like what
a huge bonus that was right to have a
guy that performed like a number one
corner. That's how he performed like a
number one corner. Um, so I I think you
can maybe look at that position if
you're a little concerned about Cam Hart
and kind of how dinged up he's been here
early in his career to to build a little
bit more depth there. But then you have
Nico Reed that you're very excited
about. You have the return of Eric
Rogers that you might be very excited
about. We all know how we feel about
Tarhee. I expect him to take a jump
again in year three. I look at the
linebacker room. You know, I'm excited
about Marlo Wax, man. after what I saw
in preseason and what I saw in that
Denver game.
>> Uh I'm excited about a a lot. And look,
Junior Coulson, like I I know that's not
a popular name with people watching and
listening right now, but this was the
guy that we were pining for that man, if
you can get the quarterback of that
Michigan defense, the rave reviews you
had on him, and I think it's just a dude
that's been snake bit his first two
years. and Popper and I were talking
about this and it's like I'll just I'll
never forget standing on that practice
field that first day that I saw him jog
out and I just went my god like
>> dudes that you want Yes. There's certain
guys you want walking off that bus first
and Junior Coulson's about, you know,
Adafo,
Junior Coulson, Derwin James, those are
guys you want walking off the bus first
to to make sure if the offense is
standing there to kind of let know,
yeah, yeah, that's what's coming for you
today. So, I'm excited. Like point I'm
getting at is I think you can make the
case of, yeah, let's help out Chris
Olirri. You know, the guy just
coordinated his first defense last year.
Let's make sure he's got everything he
needs. We know what Mike McDaniel's
capable of doing, what what Shawn McVey
can do, what Kyle Shanahan can do with
maybe a little bit less based on how
great they are at Colin and how great
they are at scheming it up. Um, but to
me I think I think you can just do the
best player available because they're
still, you know, with Tart and Ooway and
Tulie and Khalil and even if you bring
back Deshan Han with with Deon who I
think kind of had a little bit of a
rough patch there but I thought came
back pretty darn strong with with Marlo
if you bring back DP at a reasonable
number again to to give you some depth
in that veteran presence and with the
return of Junior like I just I feel like
they're pretty good man. I feel like,
you know, RJ Mickens, Elijah Turwind, I
think corner is the one spot where you
could circle and say, "All right, if one
of these guys slides, if one of these
really good corners slides, then then
yeah, that's the one where you could
say, "Hey, we got a first round on this
guy and he's sliding. Let's let's not
trade back. Let's go ahead and scoop him
up."
>> Money, I I wrote down Marlo Wax and
Junior Coulson, their cap numbers. Marlo
Wax, 1.06 million. Junior Cole at 1.6
million. The the best thing that could
have happened to this team in week 18,
we're having some of those backups play.
They kept Bo Knicks and the number one
seated Broncos out of the end zone the
entire afternoon. Barlo Wax was on the
field. So, I I I think that that is a
name in July and August that we're going
to be really excited about seeing in
those first couple of preseason games.
And you know, the the linebacker depth
is something that I I certainly want to
talk to folks about at at the combine,
but I just I I like I like the potential
of some of these guys that, you know,
you mentioned guys like R.J. Mickens who
had a stretch there where he had like
three or four picks in prime time. Like
he had he had some really big games.
>> Um let's go to
our our Nate our guy Nate Gazny. Love
the work you guys do. What is the
possibility for Keenan to return as wide
receiver 4? Feels like Jirro was unable
to balance his role with the others.
McDaniel may be able to use him in
smaller stints. I I think that that's
something that will time will tell. Uh
if if Keenan wants to continue to play
and and be in Los Angeles and I'm sure
those talks with Mike McDaniel and
Keenan Allen uh will will happen
probably sooner than later. And you
know, I'd love to see number 13 back in
the mix and uh for this wide receiver uh
group to have really defined roles in
and how they attack opposing defenses.
>> Yeah, I think with Keenan it's probably
a number. You know, we know Keenan likes
to get play paid. he really likes to get
paid and I think he kind of views that I
think it's a he likes the money but I
also think he views it as a form of
respect and I think he he takes issue
with with being paid less than other
players that he sees as far inferior to
him which I understand. I I totally get
that. Um so I think that's kind of what
it'll probably come down to. And I do
think it's it's also I I think that's
secondary. The number one thing is it's
all Mike McDaniel. It's a 100% Mike
McDaniel of saying and working with
Justin of I know he's kind of been that
guy that's extended drives and been sort
of your your hot read on every third
down and you can trust him and that's
super important to extend drives, but
this is how I see it. This is how I can
see us configuring it. Does that work
for you? Um, you know, I I I think
Trey's ready. That That's just I I do I
think he's ready. I I I have
>> I think he's going to be a special
player. I just do, man. I think he's
going to be a really He's so smart. Um
he is so incredibly smart and so
incredibly tough. And I just assume row
with those three, man. I'm I'm good. If
you tell me they're rolling out there
with Q, Lad, and and Trey, I'm good. Um,
I I I just, you know, I feel like I feel
pretty good with those three. They block
their tails off. I think Lad, we've
talked about it. We we we talked about
it so much, Chris. I don't need to
belver the point. You know, lads lads a
one lad. Wait till I I can't wait to see
what Mike McDaniel does with Lad Maki.
Like, I cannot wait. It's going to be
it's going to be so fun. It's going to
be so freaking fun.
>> You got to put on your uh your NFL
fantasy hat uh from a few years ago. Lad
lad's going to be in the conversation.
He's he's gonna have a lot of lot of
receptions, a lot of yards, a lot of
touchdowns.
>> I I think the fact that that uh this
draft seems to be so loaded at wide
receiver will will help the Chargers in
the second and third round. You talk
about drafting Trey Harris last year,
lad in the uh second round, the year
before, Quinton in the first round, a
couple years before that. Uh I I think
that there's an opportunity to maybe get
other other positions in the second and
third round while that run on wide
receivers happens to go. Um, Nate also
had a good question that I think I want
to see for for Joe. Uh, does the current
regime have specific combine thresholds
that they abide by? Uh, just things that
they look for at the combine. So, we can
ask Joe that next week. Um,
>> yeah. Louise, uh, what do you think will
be an important need in Mike's offense?
Example, an all-around tight end, extra
blocking offensive line for jumbo sets,
even a gadget player. Excited for the
trench player drills at the combine.
Would love two of the first three picks
to be trench editions. So, what what do
you think Mike McDaniel needs that maybe
isn't currently on the roster, Mike?
>> Um, yeah. To me, I I think he'd love to
have that, you know, and it's not that Q
can't do it. It's just not what he does
best. I know the numbers would say that,
you know, his targets, his, you know,
his receptions were downfield throws,
but I just I I think that Q is so good
on the move and those short those short
quick hitters, you know, run after catch
sort of plays where if you can find that
X,
open it up, man. Let's go. Let Let's
open this thing up. and now we've got
all this underneath that we can play
with. We've got the middle of the field
for the tight end. We've got these
crossers and he's so good at drawing
this stuff up. Um, so I think that's one
I think there's a reason why DJ mocked
Kenyan City to to the Chargers because I
do think there's still a little bit of
work that needs to be done in that tight
end room just because you know Aronda we
all believe he's going to be a special
player but that's one guy like you're
going to need some more dudes in in that
room. So, I think that's uh the other
thing and and what we've already talked
about is the obvious, right? Just making
sure that interior line is right. Um I
think you're good at running back. I
think for the most part wide receivers,
like I said, I think that's that's the
one thing I would look at as opposed to
like a as much as I love Keenan, I think
you're if you're going to spend some
money, it's it's better off. you know, I
think he's going to be too expensive,
but an Alec Pierce type is just blazing
fast, sure hands, and can really open
things up.
>> The the blocking tight end, you know,
Tucker Fisk, free agent, Tyler Conklin,
Will Dley, those guys are not here. So,
who who who fills those roles and and is
it is does that come from the draft?
Does that come from free agency? Do you
resign some of those guys? Um, Alex, uh,
we only have about four more. We'll try
to buzz through these. I want to get to
everybody. Screens seem uh like easy
yards watching from my couch, but
>> I'm sure it's harder than it looks. What
elements does a team need to be great in
the screen game and how will Mike
McDaniel bring that to the Chargers?
>> For me, buddy, it just starts with Mike
McDaniel. It starts with execution and
having everybody in the right place. I
think that the pieces uh for the most
part uh are in place. Guys like Lad,
guys like Q. Um I think you need
athletic linemen. Uh, but I think just
from an execution standpoint, Mike
McDaniel has proven year over year that
he puts these guys in the best position
to execute plays.
>> Yeah, look, I to me it's it's the play
caller, right? It's recognizing the
defense
>> in a formation that, you know, you can
take advantage of with a quick, you
know, with with with a quick hitter,
with an easy button.
>> And that's what it comes down to. And I
thought like that's what was so
interesting about and I don't know if
interesting is the right word but um
that's what was so interesting about
Greg Roman is they were there and it's
like oh yeah there it is and it's like
but then it's not there anymore and it's
like why did we not go back to that you
know that wide receiver or that tight
end screen game was working so well.
Like think about Tyler Conklin in that
first game against the Chiefs. There
were like two or three of those and then
the guy never got a target the rest of
his time in in LA. It's like oh I
thought I thought that worked. And then
there was like the the Kamani Videll
like screen game and it's like that's
okay. I guess it's not working. Like it
was just very
>> strange. So I think a lot of that is on
the play caller and we know how much
Mike McDaniel loves it. like he is very
passionate about exploiting
opportunities
um and doing the homework and
recognizing a tell and and you know like
the Darren Waller Johnny Manzel
conversation that you tal that you
reposted that we talked about like those
sort of things is how he works that's
what what goes into it and I think a lot
of it is just it's eye candy it's motion
it's making the defense uncomfortable um
you know I don't remember was it. Was it
McDaniel that said it or was it Chris
Olir that said it? I can't remember who
said it, but it was just such a cool
sort of insightful thing to say is, you
know, what's a defense trying to do?
Guess the answer to a question that they
don't have the answer for that the the
offense has the answer. The the defense
does not and they're trying to figure
out what that answer is. So, the more
variables you can put into that question
that make it a harder question to
answer, the better. And that's what
McDaniel is so good at. Whether it's
lining up a slot receiver in the back
field with the running back, whether
it's stacking four receivers on one side
of the line on the, you know, on the on
the the B the the hashes don't matter as
much in in the NFL, but stacking four
receivers on one just creating confusion
and second-guessing. Um, what was the
line that Chris Olirri had about about
Derwin? um clarity and it's something it
was about, you know, removing the
thinking that make it makes them play
faster and like that's what defenses are
trying to do.
>> So the more you make them think, the
easier those quick hitters are going to
be because they're thinking at the snap,
what do I see? What's come? Bang. Hit
them. And that's where that quick game
and that screen game comes in.
>> Uh this is from David Elliot. Uh no,
actually, I'm sorry. This is from
Griffin. Uh, I think two players who
have made the most difference for Justin
have been Lindley and Mike Dub. Does
Trey plus a free agent center equal
that? Does adding Alt Slater combo plus
offensive guard make up for that? Justin
needs a guy he could throw it up to.
>> See, I I just go back to our our last
answer. I I think Mike McDaniel is is
the guy who's going to provide the easy
buttons. It's not going to be some
specific player. I I see where Griffin's
coming from because Mike Mike was
awesome, especially with the long ball,
but I almost feel like Keenan was more
of the security blanket for Justin over
the course of his career, especially on
third down. I just think that Mike
McDaniel is going to make things easier
for Justin all around where you're not
relying on one guy to throw it up to.
He's going to get multiple guys open.
And that's why I think that some fans
may think that there is a wide receiver
one issue as opposed to, you know, I I I
see Lad as a wide receiver one. I see
Trey Harris with the potential to be a
wide receiver one. I think using Q the
right way um is something that Mike
McDaniel can accomplish. I think getting
the most out of Aronda is something that
Mike McDaniel can accomplish. and then
catching the ball out of the back field,
which is, you know, why I mentioned a
guy like Gainwell, just another back in
the stable that can do some things to
help Justin coming out of the back
field.
>> Yeah, I mean, I I got nothing to add to
that. I think you hit it perfectly,
Chris. You know, especially with the
Amaran. Amari can catch the ball, man.
And Amaran is electric
>> with the ball in his hand. So, that to
me is
>> that's a that's a 400 receiving yard
plus back, you know, a a 34 receiving
touchdown minimum back. So to me that's
that's where a lot of that is going to
come from.
>> From David Elliot, is there value in
this year's draft where we pick or would
it be better to trade this year's pick
for draft capital next year? Is next
year's draft better talent-wise to make
the above scenario worth it? You know,
if you trade if you trade the pick, I
would assume you would just try to get a
couple of seconds this year. I mean, may
maybe you trade to get an extra pick
next year, but I don't know if there if
there's a a huge talent discrepancy
depending on what positions you want to
draft. I mean, at quarterback, it's
going to be a good quarterback class
next year, but that's not something the
Chargers need.
>> Yeah, I think they can project out and I
you and I can't, Chris, but they can,
you know, they're they're the ones that
do it. So they can project out a year
and say, "Hey, next year's going to be a
really good corner class, edge class,
center cl, that kind of stuff." Um,
yeah, I do think I think they always
look I they were very close to trading
that pick this past year. Very close. So
I think they look at
we we're at pick 22. We have zero first
round grade first round graded players
left. We have a grade at 22 on this
player and it's almost the exact same
grade as we have on player 45 right now
on our vertical board. So, let's trade
back, man. And if that means trading
back to 34 and picking up a one ne or or
you know or trading back to like 48 and
picking up a one next year or if it
means trading back to like 33 and
picking up pick 63 or 61 or something
like that, then yeah, that's that's what
they'll do. Um to me it all comes down
to first round grades. Do you have a
first round grade on the player that's
sitting there staring at you? And if you
don't, how much value can extract from a
team that does have a first round grade
on a player that's sitting there and
they want to take advantage of?
>> Yeah. All right, we got we got three
more. Peter, uh maybe this is more of a
statement than a question, but I don't
get fans who want to kick QJ out.
McDaniel can tap into what he did at TCU
rather than misuse him. Uh love where
this is going. Love the pod. Cheers. And
BTFU.
Uh Peter, I agree. I think I think Q can
can really thrive here. I and Q is
taking a step every single year, money.
>> Yeah. I mean, I I don't think you're
going to get the draft compensation that
would make it worth it to move on. You
know, someone wants to send you a high
two or a one, then you're probably going
to listen. But I think out outside of
that, you know, I think if someone
called and and offered a two or a one,
then you've got to that's that's the
conversation you have with with Coach
McDaniel, like, hey, how do you how do
you value? What do you visualize? How
much? But I I think you look at Q's last
two years and you ask, you know, how how
does this fit in with what you would
want from a wide receiver three, you'd
say that's that's an A-level wide
receiver three, if not mid-tier to upper
tier wide receiver 2. Like you're in
that convers, you know, mid-tier wide
receiver, too. Great. You told me that's
what I was drafting with a second round
pick. I'm in, you know, and so
>> the the fifth year option is is
something that's probably gonna hap it's
going to happen soon. We'll probably
figure that out soon, Ro.
>> Yeah, that's the thing is I that's going
to be that's a very big number and I
think you would have to expect to see
again I thought he took a jump this year
from last year and so you would have to
see another jump um to to kind of to
feel pretty good about that. you know,
he he'd have to be in that 11200,
you know, that 75,100
10 TD range to feel good about saying
fifth year. It's 20 million bucks or
whatever it's going to be, 18, 19, 20
million bucks.
>> Yeah. Uh Brandon Johnson, outside of the
Mike McDaniel hire, who's been your
guys' top hire so far and what do they
bring? Well, we just I just saw the news
that Sanjay Lull and Shane Day are
coming back. Um I think Jordan Schulz
may have reported that. Um I I was going
to say the name Denzel Martin, the
outside linebackers coach from the
Pittsburgh Steelers that is joining
Chris Oir's staff. This is a guy who has
been with Mike Tomlin since 2016. Has
coached guys like Watt and Heismith. And
you you add a veteran coach to an
already veteranladen coaching staff, it
just I think it just it strengthens the
defensive staff. It gives Oly another
veteran coach to lean on in his first
year as defensive coordinator. We've
talked so much about the offense, Bunny,
but I I do think that, you know, I I
just I love what Chris Oolir brings to
this team. He brings that that energy
and just kind of a a a new school way of
thinking, but he's got a heck of a staff
and I think Denzel Martin is a new uh a
nice new piece to it.
>> Yeah. Look, I I I think for for me it's
Look, the coaches are great. We we've
talked about this at Nauseium. You know,
I I I think anyone they bring in I'm
going to have full faith in. Um but to
me, it's it's Mike McDaniel, man. Like I
I don't need to get any deeper than
that. Like it's going to change. so so
much like it's it is going to change so
much um to have you know when you take
head co play calling head coaches out of
the mix like Shanahan Shawn McVey this
is the best offensive coordinator in the
league and he's on the Chargers and he's
working with Justin Herbert like that's
to me like I don't need to get too deep
into the weeds I know some people you
know would like to like what do you
think of the you know what do
Sanjay Law, Shane Day, Mike Ston, Steve
Clingscale, like we can get through it.
And it's like, yeah, man. It's it's
ultimately, and that's the one thing
that's great about the fact that all
those guys are coming back for for Chris
Oolir is you've got that continuity in
the position, you know, in those rooms.
Um, but yeah, to me, it's it's it's
McDaniel. Like, it's I can't wait. I
truly I cannot wait to see what it looks
like.
>> Yeah. You know, we we mentioned guys
like Adam Gay and it it comes down to
the guy who's in charge of the offense
and and like like you said, man, I I
can't wait till even like
>> OTAAS. I I I'm excited for just mini
camp just to kind of see just the the
little flashes of what we're going to
see in the fall. Uh this is the last
question, life advice. Uh Cecilia
Winters,
>> uh advice for getting into the industry.
I run Chargers Check-in the YouTube
channel and I want to do NFL analysis
analysis for a living. Appreciate you
both. Mighty want to give it a crack?
>> Yeah, I think just keep doing that. You
know, it's so different from when we got
in. We're old men, so you know, we had
to to, you know, chop wood and carry
water for people and and hope they would
give you a crack here, you know, a shot
here or there. Now you can just do it
yourself. And I think, you know, you see
so many good Charger podcasts out there
and Charger YouTube shows and, you know,
whether that's you, I mean, I I would I
don't want to list them individually
because I feel bad about leaving any of
those guys out, but I think we're really
fortunate as a team to have so many
great, you know, pods. And I think keep
running charge your check-in. Watch
yourself back. Be critical. Think about
if that's something that that you
thought was compelling enough that you
would spend. However, if you're doing a
30 minute show, would you want to spend
30 minutes watching it? And if not,
figure out what you need to do
differently and just keep getting reps,
man. And um that's that's the best thing
I can I can offer up. I think you're
you're already doing it. So, just keep
doing it. And it there there's nothing
stopping you from being the next one
that that catches on and building from
30 f, you know, 30 viewers to 300 to
3,000.
>> No question. It's it's the consistency
with it. And I'll echo what you said
about just the Chargers content
community. There's so many different
ways to consume Chargers content, so
many really good podcasts. Just be be
you, but also find a little different
flavor. Find something that maybe people
aren't doing. and, you know, bring on
interesting guests and just continue to
show that passion because I I tell you
what, we've seen from when this team
moved up from San Diego to Los Angeles,
just each and every year I feel like I
see a new content creator or a new
podcast or a new voice talking about the
team and uh it's it's really refreshing
to, you know, you learn from other
people, too. So, Cecilia, appreciate you
watching us and uh wish you the best.
Uh, Muddy, you got a you got a few more
stops uh on your tour before I see you
in Indie. Anything else before we get
out of here, brother?
>> Just looking forward to it, man. It's
one of my favorite times of the year. We
got so many people to treat us great and
give us their time. And I would expect
as uh hopefully I'm going to lean on you
a little bit more this time around and
and and Brian and Tyler to to put this
thing together as I'm busy lugging gear
around and and driving kids up and down
the eastern seabboard. But um expect to
see a really good guest list of of
people that you love to hear from. A lot
of our friends have been really good to
us and I expect them to continue uh
doing that. So, you know, talking about
what the future looks like. It's an
exciting team. Coaching staff exciting
players exciting Justin Herbert for
goodness sakes. Uh as coach said, he's
got to get him in the Hall of Fame,
which means he's probably got to win a
Super Bowl. So, let's get that Super
Bowl under his belt. maybe an MVP in the
same year and uh and and welcome one of
the bright young defensive minds into
the NFL and Chris Olri at 33 years old
and coordinating a heck of a defense and
it all kind of starts. This is exactly
the starting point. You know, the
combine is where 2026 begins. So, it's
it's pretty fun to to know that it's a
couple days away, Chris.
>> Yeah, we we officially really kind of
kick off the off seasonason at the
combine because we're talking about free
agency. We're talking about the draft.
We're hearing from so many different
voices that we heard from last year
about the team and what what they feel
like uh is the missing piece or pieces
to eventually hoist that Lombardi. So,
it's uh again, it's one of my favorite
weeks as well. We're going to have three
podcasts next week. I think Tuesday,
Wednesday, Thursday, maybe even four. It
depends on how many guests we get, but
we usually get quite a few. Could be. Uh
so, uh you will not be short of Chargers
content next week. Money, uh go enjoy
the fam. Uh, wish you guys the best. Uh,
for money up Chris.
>> This has been Chargers Weekly presented
by Split.